Guide to the Dorothy Norman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Pre-1990 Acquisitions, 1908-1983; 2; 25.25; 28 boxes
  - Dorothy Norman Correspondence
    - Drucker, Peter, 1938 (Box 70)
    - Duckett, Alfred A., 1946-1947 (Box 70)
    - Dudley, Dorothy, 1937-1949 (Box 70)
    - Dudley Gallery, 1949 March 9 (Box 70)
    - Duncan, Charles, 1954 (Box 70)
    - Dunham, Harry H., 1935-1936 (Box 70)
    - Durrell, Lawrence, 1937-1940, undated (Box 70)
    - "E" General, 1938-1963, undated (Box 70)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, 1948 (Box 70)
    - Edelman, John, 1937-1938 (Box 70)
    - Educational Directory, 1938-1945 (Box 70)
    - Ehrlich, Evelyn, 1937-1941, undated (Box 70)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1940 (Box 70)
    - Einstein, William, 1937-1949 (Box 70)
    - Elias, Robert, 1941-1942 (Box 70)
    - Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1937 (Box 70)
    - Ellington, Margaret, 1947 (Box 70)
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1937-1940 (Box 70)
    - Elmslie, George Grant, 1938-1949 (Box 70)
    - Emerson, P. H. (Peter Henry), estate of, 1953 (Box 70)
    - Engel, Lehman A., 1935-1939 (Box 70)
    - Engelhard, Agnes, 1946-1967 (Box 70)
    - Engelhard, Georgia, 1948 June 10 (Box 70)
    - Engelhardt, Louise, 1942-1949 (Box 71)
    - Enters, Angna, 1936-1960; 3 (Box 71)
      Includes newspaper clippings, press releases and other printed material relating to Angna Enters.
    - E. P. Dutton (Firm), 1938-1939 (Box 71)
    - Ermath, Fritz, 1940-1941 (Box 71)
    - Esoterica Gallery, 1955 (Box 71)
    - Estorick, Eric, 1935 November 8 (Box 71)
    - Ettinghausen, Richard, 1943-1959, undated (Box 71)
    - Evans, B., undated (Box 71)
    - Evans, Miss (daughter of Frederick Evans), 1953 November 17 (Box 71)
    - Everson, William, 1942-1945 (Box 71)
    - Ewen, David, 1937 (Box 71)
    - "F" General, 1937-1963, undated (Box 71)
    - Fairbanks, Arthur, 1947 April 22 (Box 71)
    - Fairbanks, Ruth, 1948 (Box 71)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1939 (Box 71)
    - Farrell, James, 1937 (Box 71)
    - Faure, Élie, 1938 (Box 71)
    - Feibleman, James Kern, 1938-1947 (Box 71)
    - Fenn, Charles, 1938 (Box 71)
    - Fenniger, Natalie B., 1938-1941 (Box 71)
    - Ferries, Hugh, 1949 January 3 (Box 71)
    - Ferrini, Vincent, 1943-1949 (Box 71)
    - Ferstl, Claire G., 1949 (Box 71)
    - Fesler, Caroline, 1947 April 22 (Box 71)
    - Feuillerat, Albert, 1937-1939, undated (Box 71)
    - Field, Martin, 1950 (Box 71)
    - Filler, Louis, 1938-1943 (Box 71)
    - Fischel, Marguerite, 1933-1948, undated (Box 71)
    - Fischer, Louis, 1943-1947 (Box 71)
    - Fishbein, Frieda, 1947-1948 (Box 71)
    - Fisk University, 1952 February 26 (Box 71)
    - Flanagan, Hallie, 1937-1938 (Box 71)
    - Fleischmann, Marcel, 1939 (Box 71)
    - Fles, Barthold, 1939-1943, undated (Box 71)
    - Flesch, Philipp, 1940-1946 (Box 71)
    - Flint, Ralph, 1937-1938, undated (Box 71)
    - Flores, Angel, 1937-1941 (Box 71)
    - Focus, 1939 (Box 71)
    - Follansbee, Eleanor, 1941-1942, undated (Box 71)
    - Folmer, William F. & Walter, 1947-1949 (Box 71)
    - Folsom, Franklin, 1937-1939 (Box 71)
    - Foote, Alvin, 1940-1941 (Box 71)
    - Forbes, Edward W. (Edward Waldo), 1947 (Box 71)
    - Ford, Charles Henri, 1937 (Box 71)
    - Fortune Magazine, 1945 (Box 71)
    - Fowler, Gene, 1954, undated (Box 71)
    - Fraenkel, Michael, 1937-1946 (Box 71)
    - Fraenkel, Osmond K. (Osmond Kessler), 1938-1941 (Box 71)
    - Frank, Adam, 1937 (Box 71)
    - Frank, Alma, 1946-1947 (Box 71)
    - Frank, John P. (John Paul), 1946 (Box 71)
    - Frank, Waldo David, 1932-1949, undated (Box 71)
    - Frankel, Godfrey, 1946 November 2 (Box 71)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd, 1938-1949 (Box 71)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1938-1942 (Box 71)
    - Freeman, Joseph, 1943-1948 (Box 71)
    - Freud, Sigmund, 1937 (Box 71)
    - Freund, Philip, 1940-1941 (Box 71)
    - Frick Art Reference Library, 1949 January 5 (Box 71)
    - Fried, John H. E., 1939-1943 (Box 71)
    - Friedman, Esther, 1946 October 10 (Box 71)
    - Fromm, Erich, 1953-1962 (Box 71)
    - Frost, Frances, 1938 (Box 71)
    - Fry, Christopher, 1938-1940 (Box 71)
    - Fuchs, Daniel, 1937 (Box 71)
    - "G" General, 1932-1961, undated (Box 71)
    - Gabo, Naum, 1952 (Box 71)
    - Galantière, Lewis, 1937-1938 (Box 71)
    - Gallimard (Firm), 1939-1946 (Box 71)
    - Gāndhī, Devadāsa, 1950-1954 (Box 71)
    - Gandhi, Indira, 1965-1980; 4 (Box 71)
    - Gandhi, Indira, 1959-1983; 2 (Box 72)
    - Gascoyne, David, 1938-1942 (Box 72)
    - Gehman, Richard B., 1944-1945 (Box 72)
    - Geismar, Maxwell David, 1938-1940, undated (Box 72)
    - Gellert, Hugo, 1949 February 9 (Box 72)
    - George Allen & Unwin, 1937 (Box 72)
    - Géraud, André, 1944-1958, undated (Box 72)
    - Gernsheim, Helmut, 1953-1963 (Box 72)
    - Gertler, Maynard, 1949 January 26 (Box 72)
    - Gessner, Robert, 1937 (Box 72)
    - Gianturco, Elio, 1937-1940 (Box 72)
    - Gide, André, 1937-1938 (Box 72)
    - Gilbert, Stuart, 1938 (Box 72)
    - Gittelson, Bernard, 1945, undated (Box 72)
    - Glaser, Dorothy, 1937-1939 (Box 72)
    - Glasgold, C. Adolph, 1937 (Box 72)
    - Glassman, Baruch, 1937, undated (Box 72)
    - Gleisner, Martin, 1941, undated (Box 72)
    - Goldman, Emma, 1937-1938 (Box 72)
    - Goldsborough, Marta, 1938-1944 (Box 72)
    - Goldschmidt, Jacques, 1947 (Box 72)
    - Goldwater, S. S. (Sigismund Schulz), 1937-1938 (Box 72)
    - Goll, Claire, 1939-1947 (Box 72)
    - Gollancz, Victor, 1938-1939 (Box 72)
    - Goodland, John, 1938-1939 (Box 72)
    - Goodman, Ezra, 1940, undated (Box 72)
    - Goodman, Paul, 1941-1947 (Box 72)
    - Goodrich, Lloyd, 1956-1957 (Box 72)
    - Goodyear, Conger, 1947-1954 (Box 72)
    - Gooler, Sael, 1940 (Box 72)
    - Gordon, Paul, 1940 (Box 72)
    - Gorelik, Mordecai, 1937 (Box 72)
    - Gotham Book Mart, 1937-1950 (Box 72)
    - Gottlieb, Elaine, 1942-1947 (Box 72)
    - Goyen, William, 1946-1947 (Box 72)
    - Graf, Oskar Maria, 1940-1948 (Box 72)
    - Graff, Robert D., 1954-1961, undated (Box 72)
    - Graham, Martha, 1951 (Box 72)
    - Graves, Morris, 1960-1978 (Box 72)
    - Greene, Jane, 1941-1942 (Box 72)
    - Greer, Scott, 1945-1947, undated (Box 72)
    - Gregory, Alyse, 1937-1938 (Box 72)
    - Gregory, Horace, 1953-1958 (Box 72)
    - Griggs, L. S., 1937 (Box 72)
    - Gronowicz, Anthony, 1941-1950, undated (Box 72)
    - Gropius, Walter, 1937-1949 (Box 72)
    - Grossberg, Paul, 1941-1942 (Box 72)
    - Grosz, George, 1937-1940 (Box 72)
    - Guénon, René, 1937-1940 (Box 72)
    - Guilloux, Louis, 1937-1938 (Box 72)
    - Guitar, Mary Anne, 1941-1943 (Box 72)
    - Gumpert, Martin, 1937-1946 (Box 72)
    - Gussow, Bernard, undated (Box 72)
    - Gustafson, Ralph, 1941 (Box 72)
    - Guteman, Ernest, 1946-1951 (Box 72)
    - "H" General, 1933-1961, undated; 2 (Box 73)
    - Hachette (Firm), 1946 (Box 73)
    - Haddon Craftsmen, Inc., 1938-1948 (Box 73)
    - Haines, George, 1940 (Box 73)
    - Hamilton, Walton Hale, 1939-1946 (Box 73)
    - Hanna, L. C., Jr. (Leonard Colton), 1947 May 20 (Box 73)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1937-1939 (Box 73)
    - Hapgood, Neith, 1947-1948, undated (Box 73)
    - Harcourt Brace & Company, 1938-1945 (Box 73)
    - Hardt, Ludwig, 1942 (Box 73)
    - Harlem Book Company, 1940-1950 (Box 73)
    - Harper, Carol Ely, 1946-1949 (Box 73)
    - Harper & Brothers, 1938-1948 (Box 73)
    - Harris, Marguerite Tjader, 1940-1947 (Box 73)
    - Harris, Roy, 1937-1940 (Box 73)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1916-1940, undated (Box 73)
    - Hartman, Bertram & Gusta, 1939-1947 (Box 73)
    - Harvey, Dorothy Dudley, 1947, undated (Box 73)
    - Haserot, Francis Samuel, 1937 (Box 73)
    - Haskell, Ernest, Jr., 1948 January 7 (Box 73)
    - Haydon, Stuart, 1945 (Box 73)
    - Hayman, Lee Richard, 1946-1949 (Box 73)
    - Hayes, Bartlett H., Jr., 1947-1949 (Box 73)
    - Hayward, Dorothy R., 1938-1939 (Box 73)
    - Ház, Nicholas, 1947-1949, undated (Box 73)
    - Healy, J. V., 1940 (Box 73)
    - Heiden, Konrad, 1941-1942 (Box 73)
    - Hélion, Jean, 1937 (Box 73)
    - Henderson, Evelyn, 1938-1939, undated (Box 73)
    - Herrmann, Eva, 1947 (Box 73)
    - Herskovits, Melville, Jr., 1937 (Box 73)
    - Herter Norton, M. D. (Mary Dows), 1937-1941 (Box 73)
    - Heyman, Ruth, 1946-1948, undated (Box 73)
    - Hiebel, Frederick, 1946 (Box 73)
    - Hindus, Milton, 1946-1949 (Box 73)
    - Hobson, Laura Keane Zametkin, 1947-1949, undated (Box 73)
    - Hoffman, Malvina, 1947 July 10 (Box 73)
    - Hoch, Peter, 1941-1942 (Box 73)
    - Holt, Claire, 1958-1959 (Box 73)
    - Holtman, Alice, 1948 (Box 73)
    - Holbrook, May, 1937-1940 (Box 73)
    - Holbrook, Sabra, 1945-1946 (Box 73)
    - Holmes, Jack, 1938-1945 (Box 73)
    - Holtman, Alice, 1939-1941, undated (Box 73)
    - Honig, Edwin, 1942-1943 (Box 73)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1938 (Box 73)
    - Hope, Henry R. (Henry Radford), 1947 June 28 (Box 73)
    - Horizon, 1940-1941 (Box 73)
    - Horton, Philip Clark, 1937-1938 (Box 73)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1937-1947 (Box 73)
    - Houston, Peyton, 1941-1942 (Box 73)
    - Howard, E. (Evelyn), 1931-1938, undated (Box 73)
    - Howard, Richard Foster, 1931-1937 (Box 73)
    - Huberman, Leo, 1937-1938 (Box 73)
    - Huebsch, B. W. (Benjamin W.), 1947 June 24 (Box 73)
    - Hughes, Jim J., 1943, undated (Box 73)
    - Human Affairs, 1949-1950 (Box 73)
    - Humphreys-Roberts, G., 1938 (Box 73)
    - Humphries, Rolfe, 1938-1939 (Box 73)
    - Hutchinson, Edith, 1947 March 18 (Box 73)
    - Huxley, Aldous, 1937 (Box 73)
    - "I" General, 1938-1948 (Box 73)
    - Ignatoff, David, 1946-1947 (Box 73)
    - Imbs, Bravig, 1937 (Box 73)
    - Indianapolis Public Library, 1952 (Box 73)
    - Institute of Contemporary Art (Boston, Mass.), 1949 February 9 (Box 73)
    - International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1946-1947 (Box 73)
    - Irene, Princess of Greece, 1935-1949 (Box 73)
    - Irwin, Theodore, 1939 (Box 73)
    - Isaacson, Joseph D., 1944-1945 (Box 73)
    - Iselin, O'Donnell, 1949 January 3 (Box 73)
    - Ives, Charles E., 1937-1941 (Box 73)
    - Ives, Halsey Cooley, 1947 June 27 (Box 73)
    - Ivins, William, 1946-1949 (Box 73)
    - "J" General, 1937-1962, undated (Box 73)
    - Jaffé, Arthur, 1938-1948 (Box 73)
    - James, Earle K., 1941 (Box 73)
    - Jeffers, Robinson, 1937 (Box 73)
    - Jewell, Edward Alden, 1939-1946 (Box 73)
    - Joad, C. E. M. (Cyril Edwin Mitchinson), 1937-1938 (Box 73)
    - Johannsen, Edith, 1941 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1937-1947 (Box 73)
    - Johnston, J. Dudley, 1947-1953 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, Ernest E., 1945 (Box 73)
    - Johnson, Margot, 1937-1941 (Box 73)
    - Joseph, J. Calder (John Calder), 1940-1947, undated (Box 73)
    - Josephson, Matthew, 1937-1946 (Box 73)
    - Junior Bazaar, 1947 (Box 73)
    - "K" General, 1935-1962, undated (Box 73)
    - Kafka, Franz, 1940-1946 (Box 73)
      Includes material relating to Franz Kafka.
    - Kahler, Erich, 1939-1948 (Box 73)
    - Kahn, Hannah, 1945-1948 (Box 73)
    - Kahn, Lina, 1941-1942 (Box 73)
    - Kallen, Horace Meyer, 1940-1942 (Box 73)
    - Kalonyme, Louis, 1949-1954 (Box 73)
    - Karger, Arthur, 1942-1943 (Box 73)
    - Karpman, Benjamin, 1945 (Box 73)
    - Katz, Leo, 1933-1946 (Box 73)
    - Kauder, Hugo, 1940 (Box 73)
    - Kaun, Alexander, 1938-1939 (Box 73)
    - Kazin, Alfred, 1942-1948, undated (Box 73)
    - Keene, Frances, 1939-1948, undated (Box 74)
    - Kellog, Walter, 1938 (Box 74)
    - Kelly, D. E., 1949 February 21 (Box 74)
    - Kelly, Richard, 1946 (Box 74)
    - Kempees & Stevens, 1946-1948 (Box 74)
    - Kennerley, Mitchell, 1939-1951, undated (Box 74)
    - Kenyon College. Library., 1946-1947 (Box 74)
    - Kerr, Harrison, 1937-1939, undated (Box 74)
    - Kilgore Committee, 1945 (Box 74)
    - Kimball, Fiske, 1947 October 21 (Box 74)
    - King, Carol, 1939 (Box 74)
    - Kirchwey, Freda, 1941 (Box 74)
    - Kirkpatrick, John, 1940, undated (Box 74)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1949 March 30 (Box 74)
    - Kiskadden, Margaret Rodakiewicz, undated (Box 74)
    - Klein, Lidia, 1947 March 18 (Box 74)
    - Klingenhofer, Doris, 1947, undated (Box 74)
    - Klitgaard, Kaj, 1938-1949 (Box 74)
    - Kneering, Mr., 1949 February 28 (Box 74)
    - Knox, Israel, 1936-1938 (Box 74)
    - Koch, Carl, 1951 December 6 (Box 74)
    - Koestler, Arthur, 1942-1951, undated (Box 74)
    - Kohn, Hans, 1948-1955 (Box 74)
    - Konvitz, Milton R. (Milton Ridvas), 1929-1948 (Box 74)
    - Kootz, Samuel Melvin, 1947 October 22 (Box 74)
    - Kopman, Benjamin, 1937-1947 (Box 74)
    - Koppell, H. G., 1938-1942 (Box 74)
    - Kornfeld, Kurt, 1937-1938, undated (Box 74)
    - Korzybski, Alfred, 1937-1938 (Box 74)
    - Kramer, Samuel Noah, 1947-1958 (Box 74)
    - Kraus, Hans Felix, 1939-1942 (Box 74)
    - Krause, Friedrich, 1939 (Box 74)
    - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1937-1948 (Box 74)
    - Kubie, Lawrence S. (Lawrence Schlesinger), 1951-1962 (Box 74)
    - Kucern, Hubert, 1949 (Box 74)
    - Kuhn, Hedwig, 1954 May 13 (Box 74)
    - Kuniholm, Stanley, 1948, undated (Box 74)
    - Khushwant Singh, 1952-1958, undated (Box 74)
    - "L" General, 1938-1962, undated (Box 74)
    - L. B. Fischer Publishing Corporation, 1942-1943 (Box 74)
    - Lachaise, Isabel, 1937-1957, undated (Box 74)
    - The Lakeside Press, 1938-1948 (Box 74)
    - Lamb, Beatrice, 1940-1946, undated (Box 74)
    - Lang, Daniel, 1940 (Box 74)
    - Lasky, Mr., 1952 July 29 (Box 74)
    - Latimer, Ronald Lane, 1937-1938 (Box 74)
    - Latzko, Andreas, 1940-1946 (Box 74)
    - Laughlin, Ann, 1956, undated (Box 74)
    - Laughlin, Clarence John, 1940-1941 (Box 74)
    - Laughlin, James, 1944-1953, undated (Box 74)
    - Laughlin, Jay, 1937-1946 (Box 74)
    - Lawrence, Frieda von Richthofen, 1937 (Box 74)
    - Lawrence, Jessie, 1935-1941 (Box 74)
    - Lawrence, Robert, 1955-1960, undated (Box 74)
    - Lechlitner, Ruth, 1938 (Box 74)
    - Ledermann, Minna, 1941 (Box 74)
    - Lee, Amy Freeman, 1942-1943 (Box 74)
    - Leffert, Henry, 1938-1939 (Box 74)
    - Lehmann, Leo, 1943 September 27 (Box 74)
    - Leipzig Royal Fine Arts Academy, 1951 November 29 (Box 74)
    - Lennon, Florence Becker, 1939 (Box 74)
    - Léon, Felipe, 1939-1940 (Box 74)
    - Leiser, John, 1942-1944 (Box 74)
    - Lemont, Jessie, 1940 (Box 74)
    - Lerman, Leo, 1949, undated (Box 74)
    - Lerner, Max, 1938-1946; 2 (Box 74)
    - Lescaze, Mary Hughes, 1937-1956, undated; 3 (Box 74)
    - Lescaze, William, 1937-1949; 2 (Box 74)
    - Levi, Carlo, 1947-1959, undated (Box 74)
    - Levin, Alvin Frederick, 1939 (Box 74)
    - Levitt, Frances, 1946-1953 (Box 74)
    - Levy, Julien, 1952, undated (Box 75)
    - Lewis, H. H., 1939-1940, undated (Box 75)
    - Lewis, Robert, 1940-1955, undated (Box 75)
    - Leyda, Jay, 1948, undated (Box 75)
    - Liben, Meyer, 1941-1944 (Box 75)
    - Library of Congress, 1940-1945 (Box 75)
    - Liddle, Hesper, 1948, undated (Box 75)
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1937-1942 (Box 75)
    - Liebovitz, David, 1947-1948 (Box 75)
    - Liebman, Charles, 1946-1953 (Box 75)
    - Life Magazine, 1939-1946 (Box 75)
    - Lincoln Warehouse Corporation, 1950-1952 (Box 75)
    - Lindey, Alexander, 1940-1945 (Box 75)
    - Lippman, Frances A., 1939-1948 (Box 75)
    - Litvinov, M. M. (Maksim Maksimovich), 1943, undated (Box 75)
    - Lloyd, McAllister, 1937-1939 (Box 75)
    - Locher, Robert Evans, 1951-1954 (Box 75)
    - Loeb, Elinor G., 1939 (Box 75)
    - London Camera Club, 1949 March 9 (Box 75)
    - London Gallery, 1938-1939 (Box 75)
    - London Photographic Salon, 1949 March 9 (Box 75)
    - London Times, 1948 (Box 75)
    - Lopez, Robert S. (Robert Sabatino), 1943 September 22 (Box 75)
    - Los Angeles County Museum, 1948 January 2 (Box 75)
    - Losey, Joseph, 1937 (Box 75)
    - Lourie, Nora, 1937, undated (Box 75)
    - Lovejoy, Arthur O. (Arthur Oncken), 1937, undated (Box 75)
    - Low, A. Ritchie, 1945-1946, undated (Box 75)
    - Lowe-Porter, H. T. (Helen Tracy), 1939 (Box 75)
    - Lowenfeld, Margaret, 1958-1964 (Box 75)
    - Lowry, Robert, 1941-1942 (Box 75)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1937-1943, undated (Box 75)
    - Lyons, Edward, 1940-1948 (Box 75)
    - "M" General, 1937-1964, undated; 2 (Box 75)
    - Maas, Willard, 1938 (Box 75)
    - Macdonald, Dwight, 1940-1948, undated (Box 75)
    - Macdonald-Wright, Stanton, 1946-1948, undated (Box 75)
    - MacDuffie, Marshall, 1938-1939 (Box 75)
    - MacIntyre, C. F. (Carlyle Ferren), 1937-1947 (Box 75)
    - Mack, Gerstle, 1937 (Box 75)
    - Mackworth, Cecily, 1938, undated (Box 75)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1938-1945 (Box 75)
    - Macmillan Company, 1939-1943 (Box 75)
    - Macpherson, Bryher, 1938-1940 (Box 75)
    - Madison, Charles A., 1941-1944 (Box 75)
    - Magazine Digest, 1940-1943 (Box 75)
    - Magazine of Art, 1948-1949 (Box 75)
    - Maier, Joseph, 1947-1948 (Box 75)
    - Makepeace, LeRoy, 1948 (Box 75)
    - Mallan, Lloyd, 1939-1943 (Box 75)
    - Mallea, Edward, 1939 (Box 75)
    - Malraux, André, 1937-1953 (Box 75)
    - Maltz, Albert, 1937 (Box 75)
    - Mamlock, Margaret, 1947-1953 (Box 75)
    - Mangan, Sherry, 1937, undated (Box 75)
    - Mangione, Jerre, 1937-1938 (Box 75)
    - Manheim, Ralph, 1938-1948 (Box 75)
    - Mann, Erika, 1937-1942 (Box 75)
    - Mann, Golo, 1939, undated (Box 75)
    - Mann, Klaus, 1937-1942 (Box 75)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1937-1946 (Box 75)
    - Manship, Paul, 1941 October 7 (Box 75)
      Includes letter to Alfred Stieglitz
    - Marceau, Henri, 1956-1959 (Box 75)
    - Marcus, Elli, 1946 November 11 (Box 75)
    - Margules, De Hirsh, 1940-1947 (Box 75)
    - Marin, Grace Morley, 1949 March 29 (Box 75)
    - Marin, John, 1937-1951 (Box 75)
    - Markel, Lester, 1949 (Box 75)
    - Marshall, Lenore, 1948 (Box 75)
    - Marshall, Percival, 1949 (Box 75)
    - Marstin Press Inc., 1938-1949 (Box 75)
    - Martin, Kingsley, 1950-1952 (Box 75)
    - Marvel, Josiah, 1938 (Box 75)
    - Marx, Carolyn, 1938-1939 (Box 75)
    - Marx, Olga, 1939-1940 (Box 75)
    - Maslenikov, Oleg, 1939-1940 (Box 75)
    - Mason, Helen, 1944, undated (Box 75)
    - Mather, Frank J. (Frank Jewett), 1938-1939 (Box 75)
    - Matthias, Blanche, 1937, undated (Box 75)
    - Matthias, George, 1948-1950 (Box 75)
    - Mathieu, Aaron M., 1940-1947 (Box 75)
    - Matter, Mercedes, 1953-1954 (Box 75)
    - May, A. Wilfred, 1938-1948 (Box 75)
    - May, Rollo, 1956-1961 (Box 75)
    - Mayer, Elizabeth, 1939-1940 (Box 75)
    - Mayer, Milton, 1939 (Box 75)
    - Mayer, Morris Fritz, 1945-1946 (Box 75)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1937-1938 (Box 75)
    - McAlpin, David H. (David Hunter), 1941-1948 (Box 75)
    - McBride, Henry, 1946 (Box 75)
    - McCallister, Frank, 1939 (Box 75)
    - McCausland, Elizabeth, 1937-1954 (Box 75)
    - McCormick, Ada P., 1943-1947 (Box 75)
    - McCrum, Blanche Prichard, 1947 (Box 75)
    - McIntosh, Millicent Carey, 1937-1939, undated (Box 75)
    - McIver, Loren, 1951 November 2 (Box 75)
    - McManis, John, 1946-1948 (Box 75)
    - McWilliams, Carey, 1937-1938, undated (Box 75)
    - Meitner, Clarisse, 1940 (Box 75)
    - Mellquist, Jerome, 1932-1948, undated (Box 75)
    - Mendelsohn, Luise, 1955-1956, undated (Box 75)
    - Mendeloff, Albert, 1938 (Box 75)
    - Menon, Narayana, 1958-1960 (Box 75)
    - Merriam, Eve, 1940-1942 (Box 75)
    - Messer, Mary Burt, 1938-1946 (Box 75)
    - Metcalf, Paul, 1938-1946 (Box 75)
    - Meyer, Adolf, 1937 (Box 76)
    - Meyer, Agnes Elizabeth Ernst, 1938 (Box 76)
    - Meyer, Annie Nathan, 1939-1947, undated (Box 76)
    - Meyer, Gladys, 1937-1938 (Box 76)
    - Meyer, Gerard Previn, 1937 December 16 (Box 76)
    - M. H. de Young Memorial Museum, 1947 April 3 (Box 76)
    - Michael, Jerome, 1938-1939 (Box 76)
    - Milano, Paolo, 1940-1941 (Box 76)
    - Milgram, Morris, 1942-1946 (Box 76)
    - Miller, Dorothy C., 1947 November 7 (Box 76)
    - Miller, Henry, 1937-1943 (Box 76)
    - Miller, Kenneth Hayes, 1947 December 4 (Box 76)
    - Miller, Richard, 1937 (Box 76)
    - Milliken, William Mathewson, 1946 (Box 76)
    - Milner, Lucille B., 1938-1939 (Box 76)
    - Minicam Photography, 1945, undated (Box 76)
    - Miracle, Anne, 1939, undated (Box 76)
    - Mirkine-Guetzévitch, Boris, 1951 (Box 76)
    - Misch, Robert Jay, 1939-1940 (Box 76)
    - Missouri Historical Society, 1952 (Box 76)
    - Mittelman, Gertrude, 1949 February 26 (Box 76)
    - The Modern Quarterly, 1939 (Box 76)
    - Moffitt, John, 1947 November 3 (Box 76)
    - Moïse, Howard, 1939-1941 (Box 76)
    - Mondrian, Piet, 1937-1941 (Box 76)
    - Montclair Art Museum, 1947 November 4 (Box 76)
    - Montgomery, Eleanor, 1950-1955, undated (Box 76)
    - Moon-Adams, Dabney, 1947 November 5 (Box 76)
    - Moore, Harry T., 1952 August 3 (Box 76)
    - Moore, Henry, 1938 (Box 76)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1937-1959 (Box 76)
    - Moore, Mrs. P. A., 1952 (Box 76)
    - Moore, Nicholas, 1939, undated (Box 76)
    - More, Herman, 1946 October 25 (Box 76)
    - Morgan, Anne, 1947 May 12 (Box 76)
    - Morgenthau, Rita Wallach, 1953-1958, undated (Box 76)
    - Morris, Wright, 1940-1942, undated (Box 76)
    - Motherwell, Hiram, 1943 (Box 76)
    - Mountbatten of Burma, Edwina Ashley Mountbatten, Countess, 1951-1959, undated (Box 76)
    - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel, 1943-1948 (Box 76)
    - Muir, Edwin, 1940-1941 (Box 76)
    - Mullins, Helene, 1940, undated (Box 76)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1933-1960; 3 (Box 76)
    - Munson, Gorham Bert, 1938 (Box 76)
    - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1946 September 14 (Box 76)
    - Murray, Florence, 1943 (Box 76)
    - Murray, Pauli, 1943-1946, undated (Box 76)
    - Murry, John Middleton, 1937-1947 (Box 76)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 1949 January 11 (Box 76)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1932-1960, undated (Box 76)
    - Museum of the City of New York, 1947 May 22 (Box 76)
    - Musil, Robert, 1938-1939 (Box 76)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar, 1943 November 16 (Box 76)
    - "N" General, 1938-1951 (Box 76)
    - Naess, Elsa, 1952 (Box 76)
    - Nadelman, Elie, 1949, undated (Box 76)
    - Nagel, Hildegard, 1938-1939, undated (Box 76)
    - Nagle, Elizabeth, 1948, undated (Box 76)
    - Nahm, Horace H., 1939 (Box 76)
    - Naill, Mahlon, 1942-1946 (Box 76)
    - The Nation, 1938-1947 (Box 76)
    - The National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1946 (Box 76)
    - Navenberg, F. P., 1944-1945 (Box 76)
    - Neagoe, Peter, 1937-1938 (Box 76)
    - Nehru, Jawarhalal, 1951-1964, undated (Box 76)
    - Nehru, Rajan, 1952-1955 (Box 76)
    - Neider, Charles, 1945-1947 (Box 76)
    - Neumann, Erich, 1958, undated (Box 76)
    - Neumann, J. B. (Jsrael Ber), 1951 November 28 (Box 76)
    - Neuse, Werner, 1951 March 19 (Box 76)
    - Newark Museum, 1947 (Box 76)
    - New English Weekly, 1937-1938 (Box 76)
    - Newberry Library, 1948-1949 (Box 76)
    - Newhall, Beaumont & Nancy, 1940-1957; 2 (Box 76)
    - New Masses, 1947 (Box 76)
    - New Republic, 1938-1947 (Box 76)
    - Newsweek, 1949 January 17 (Box 76)
    - New York Camera Club, 1947 March 7 (Box 76)
    - The New Yorker, 1938-1948 (Box 76)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1939-1949 (Box 76)
    - New York (N.Y.) Department of Finance, 1946-1953 (Box 76)
    - New York (State) Department of State, 1946-1947 (Box 76)
    - The New York Post, 1939-1947 (Box 76)
    - New York Public Library, 1947 September 10 (Box 76)
    - New York Times, 1939-1948 (Box 76)
    - Nicholson, Irving, 1941-1942 (Box 76)
    - Niclas, Yolla, 1946-1947 (Box 76)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1937 (Box 76)
    - Nijinsky, Romola de Pulszky, 1937-1940, undated (Box 77)
    - Nikhilananda, Swami, 1947 December 5 (Box 77)
    - Nin, Anaïs, 1936-1944, undated (Box 77)
    - Nomad, Max, 1938-1941 (Box 77)
    - Norden, Marika, 1939, undated (Box 77)
    - Norfolk Museum, 1953-1954 (Box 77)
    - Northrop, F. S. C. (Filmer Stuart Cuckow), 1947 May 27 (Box 77)
    - La Nouvelle Saison, 1938-1939 (Box 77)